Coach Jordan, how you doing? Doing
great, Shurmur. Good to see you, man.
Yes, sir. Welcome to the New York
Giants. Excited to be here. You look
great in blue. I feel great in blue. I'm
been wearing blue since college, so feel
good.
>> a little different shade. A little
different shade.
>> Yeah, but it looks good. Yes, sir. All
right, so welcome to my Cadillac IQ, the
all-new
full-sized electric SUV. Very classy
car. Yeah, here we go.
Been a little whirlwind off-season for
you? It has. It has quite different, you
know, the [music] first first one in 12
years. Yeah, yeah, you've been you've
been you've been there with with Harbs
uh for 12 years, right? Down there just
down 95? Just right down 95. Take us
through
how you went from being a player
playing in the NFL to now all of a
sudden getting into coaching.
You know, it was one of those things
where
you know, once I was done, I kind of
went back to UCLA and just really wanted
to just wanted to see if coaching is
what I wanted to do. Uh football has
always been a part of my life since I
was a young kid, so uh once I got that
opportunity to coach at UCLA, fell in
love with coaching, and then
Baltimore started a program back in
2014.
I was a part of that first that first
intern program, and you know, I I didn't
really know what to expect when I got
there, but I always knew once I left
UCLA, you know, what coaching was
something that I truly really wanted to
do. And to get the opportunity to go to
Baltimore and coach
start as an intern,
uh really just paid off. And ever since
then, it's just been working my way up.
So, you fell in love with the game just
from a different angle. Just from a
different angle. So, you you start out
as an intern, and now you're the
assistant head coach  special
teams coordinator. What what what what
is that responsibility? What does that
mean?
You know, I I don't take it very
lightly. Um you know, I again, I spend I
credit everything that uh John Harbaugh
has done for me throughout my career. He
really just put me in this in this
position
uh to be his right-hand man after after
so many years. And you know, that comes
with a a lot of responsibility. It comes
with a lot of trust. It comes with a lot
of understanding of, you know, uh
getting the message across to to
everyone and making sure that we're on
the same page. As far as being a special
teams coordinator, it was just something
that was in me. It's always been in me.
I started on the defensive side of the
ball, but I've always wanted to be a
special teams coach.
Um I love developing players, and I feel
like that's a that's a that's a room
where uh
at times it become a lost art. So, just
to have the
ability to just continue to develop guys
and help them find their opportunity.
You got a new [music] roster. You've got
some new players.
How do you go about assembling who's on
those return teams?
It's, you know, I think when you first
get in there, you find out, okay,
uh what can what can every guy do? You
know, because [music] not every guy is
going to be the same. Some guys and you
just utilize their skill set. And I
think that's what players want. Utilize
me in a way that where I'm going to have
success. And that's my job as the coach,
figuring out what the player does best.
Uh I might have a bigger guy, you know,
that is a heavy-handed two-gap player,
right? So, that guy is going to be
utilized in a way where
I'm I was going to be different than a
speed guy when I start thinking about
guys like Art Green, you know, so
just just figuring out what every guy
does. And so, the first thing I did when
I came in, I need to learn the roster.
Right. You know, so I'm sitting back,
I'm watching the tape, I'm figuring out
who's here,
um what do guys do well, what don't they
do so well, and then how can I help them
do the things that they don't do well
better? And then from there, we just
start plugging guys [music] in places.
And then as the as it goes on, we we
build out everything from there.
So, you're going to have a whole new
battery this year, obviously. Snapper,
holder, kicker. Um and that's obviously
something new. Um how how do you go
throughout that whole process?
It just you start from ground zero,
right? You you start at the bottom, and
you build them up, and and you teach
[music] them what you want. Um they're
all good players when they when they
walk in here, and you just make sure
that you hold them to the standard.
There's a lot of Some people will call
it pressure. All right, I just say, man,
you just go out there and you got to do
your job. Cuz their their job requires a
lot, you know, and when you're the
kicker, there's punts always going to be
involved. When you're the punter, you
got to flip that field. And when you're
the snapper, no one notices you until
something goes wrong.
Right? So, I just talk to them about
holding each other accountable. And work
from there. Yeah, amen.
Well, listen, Chris, we appreciate the
time. We are so excited to have you here
as part of the New York Giants. We
cannot wait for that opening kickoff.
Yes, sir. Excited to be here. All right,
thanks, man. Thank you.
>> [music]